Guide to the Mark D. Weiser Papers, 1969-1999
Department of Special Collections
- Series 16. Teaching files
  This series contains the syllabi and class materials for the courses that Mark Weiser taught at the University of Maryland as well as documents relating to the Computer Science Dept. at the University. Also contains one file on a job opportunity to teach at Duke University.
  - University of Maryland (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - University of Maryland Foundation financial ledger [1 of 2] (Box 153, Folder 2)
  - University of Maryland Foundation financial ledger [2 of 2] (Box 153, Folder 3)
  - University of Maryland. Computer Science Dept. Reusing software [1 of 3] (Box 153, Folder 4)
  - University of Maryland. Computer Science Dept. Reusing software [2 of 3] (Box 153, Folder 5)
  - University of Maryland. Computer Science Dept. Reusing software [3 of 3] (Box 153, Folder 6)
  - University of Maryland. Semantics course [1 of 3], 1984 - 1985 (Box 153, Folder 7)
  - University of Maryland. Semantics course [2 of 3], 1984 - 1985 (Box 153, Folder 8)
  - University of Maryland. Semantics course [3 of 3], 1984 - 1985 (Box 153, Folder 9)
  - A.T. & T. (Box 153, Folder 10)
  - CER (Box 153, Folder 11)
  - Color dominance paper (Box 154, Folder 1)
  - Computer art (Box 154, Folder 2)
  - Deficit (Box 154, Folder 3)
  - Dept. of Defense equipment (Box 154, Folder 4)
  - Evaluation of Berkowitz (Box 154, Folder 5)
  - Exploring programs (Box 154, Folder 6)
  - Expres Project - National Science Foundation (Box 154, Folder 7)
  - Figures (Box 154, Folder 8)
  - Forms: UMIACS (Box 154, Folder 9)
  - Graduate Research Council Subcommittee. Univ. of Maryland (Box 154, Folder 10)
  - Maryland (Box 154, Folder 11)
  - Modular building (Box 154, Folder 12)
  - Space (Box 154, Folder 13)
  - Student comments (Box 154, Folder 14)
  - UMIACS search (Box 154, Folder 15)
  - ZMOB - N.O.S. (Box 154, Folder 16)
  - Zork (Box 154, Folder 17)
  - Duke University (Box 154, Folder 18)
- Series 17. Financial Records
  This series contains personal financial documentation including check registers, bank books, paycheck stubs, tax returns, and retirement account information.
  - Allstate Auto Insurance (Box 155, Folder 1)
  - Ann Arbor Bank Passbook savings, 1972 Feb. - 1973 Mar., 2 passbooks (Box 155, Folder 2)
  - Budgets (Box 155, Folder 3)
  - Check registers (Box 155, Folder 4)
  - Expenses for Jack Callahan travel (Box 155, Folder 5)
  - Gymble account validation (Box 155, Folder 6)
  - Income tax, 1975 (Box 155, Folder 7)
  - I.R.S., 1976 (Box 155, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 155, Folder 9)
  - Naval Research Laboratory job (Box 155, Folder 10)
  - Stanford benefits portfolio (Box 155, Folder 11)
  - Taxes, 1977 (Box 155, Folder 12)
  - TIAA-CREF (Box 155, Folder 13)
  - TIAA insurance (Box 155, Folder 14)
  - Workstation/PC inventory (Box 155, Folder 15)
  - Xerox paycheck stub (Box 155, Folder 16)
- Series 18. Re-evaluation Co-counseling files
  For years, Weiser was heavily involved in Re-evaluation Co-counseling. This series contains subject files, internal memos, reports, and publications on and about the Re-evaluation Co-counseling movement.
  - A2 Re-evaluation Co-counseling News (Box 156, Folder 1)
  - Asians-Pacific Islanders (Box 156, Folder 2)
  - Re-evaluation Co-counseling: Business, order forms, etc. (Box 156, Folder 3)
  - Children (Box 156, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 156, Folder 5)
  - Fees (Box 156, Folder 6)
  - Re-evaluation Co-counseling fundamentals class (Box 156, Folder 7)
  - [Gay and Lesbian issues] (Box 156, Folder 8)
  - Handicapped (Box 156, Folder 9)
  - Handouts (Box 156, Folder 10)
  - Re-evaluation Counseling Communities. International Reference Committee (Box 156, Folder 11)
  - Jewish community (Box 156, Folder 12)
  - Jewish community (Box 156, Folder 13)
  - Jewish community (Box 156, Folder 14)
  - Re-evaluation Counseling letters (Box 156, Folder 15)
  - Men (Box 156, Folder 16)
  - Men's workshop on childcare (Box 156, Folder 17)
  - Re-evaluation Counseling: Men (Box 156, Folder 18)
  - Notebook (Box 156, Folder 19)
  - Notes (Box 156, Folder 20)
  - Receipt book, 1980 May 15 - 1982 Mar. 10 (Box 157, Folder 1)
  - Receipt book, 1975 Feb. 12 - 1980 May 16 (Box 157, Folder 2)
  - Schedule (Box 157, Folder 3)
  - Old schedules (Box 157, Folder 4)
  - Re-evaluation Counseling teachers (Box 157, Folder 5)
  - Re-evaluation Counseling thoughtful (Box 157, Folder 6)
  - Mark Weiser (Box 157, Folder 7)
  - Women (Box 157, Folder 8)
  - Workshop (Box 157, Folder 9)
  - Workshop: Dayspring II,, 1975 Apr. 18-20 (Box 157, Folder 10)
  - Workshop: Highscope,, 1976 May 28-30 (Box 157, Folder 11)
  - Workshop: The possibility of physical immortality,, 1977 Sept. 16-21 (Box 157, Folder 12)
  - Workshop: Highscope,, 1977 Oct. 28-Nov. 2 (Box 157, Folder 13)
  - Mark Weiser's workshop folder,, 1978 June 17-23 (Box 157, Folder 14)
  - Workshop: Midwest RC Teachers workshop VI, Shimer College,, 1978 June 17-23 (Box 157, Folder 15)
  - World conference (Box 157, Folder 16)
  - The benign reality / by Harvey Jackins. Seattle: Rational Island Publishers, 1981. -- 1st ed., 1981 (Box 158, Folder 1)
  - Fundamentals of co-counseling manual (elementary counselors manual) for beginning classes in re-evaluation co-counseling. -- Rev. ed. -- Seattle: Rational Island Publishers,, 1962, 1970 (Box 158, Folder 2)
  - Guidebook to re-evaluation counseling / Harvey Jackins. -- Seattle: Rational Island Publishers,, 1962, 1970 (Box 158, Folder 3)
  - The human side of human beings: the theory of re-evaluation counseling / Harvey Jackins. -- 2nd rev. ed. -- Seattle: Rational Island Publishers,, 1978 (Box 158, Folder 4)
  - The human situation / by Harvey Jackins. -- Seattle: Rational Island Publishers,, c. 1973, p. 1980 (Box 158, Folder 5)
  - Rough notes from Buck Creek I / by Harvey Jackins and others. -- Rev. ed. -- Seattle: Rational Island Publishers,, 1979 (Box 158, Folder 6)
  - Rough notes from Liberation I & II / by Harvey Jackins and others. -- Rev. ed. -- Seattle: Rational Island Publishers,, 1976 (Box 159, Folder 1)
  - Zest is best: poems / by Harvey Jackins. -- Seattle: Rational Island Publishers,, 1973 (Box 159, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets: A - D (Box 159, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets: E - N (Box 159, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets: P - T (Box 159, Folder 5)
  - Asian-American re-evaluation, nos. 2-3 (Box 160)
  - Black re-emergence, nos. 2-3 (Box 160)
  - Burst forth! (Box 160)
  - The caring parent, nos. 1-2 (Box 160)
  - The Chicago co-counselor, Vol. 6, no. 2, 1978 Apr./May (Box 160)
  - Classroom, Vol. 1, no. 1-no. 8, 1974 Summer - 1984 (Box 160)
  - Colleague, nos. 1-4 (Box 160)
  - Complete elegance, nos. 4-7 (Box 160)
  - Creativity, no. 1 (Box 160)
  - The elders speak, no. 3-4 (Box 160)
  - Forever and ever, no. 1 (Box 160)
  - Growing older, nos. 1-2 (Box 160)
  - Guidelines for the re-evaluation counseling communities, 1973 Sept.; 1977 Sept.; 1979 Sept. (Box 161)
  - Men: a journal of the re-evaluation counseling community, nos. 1-3 (Box 161)
  - Our Asian inheritance, nos. 4-5 (Box 161)
  - Pensamientos, nos. 1-3 (Box 161)
  - Present time, nos. 11-26 (Box 161)
  - Present time, nos. 27-42 (Box 162)
  - Present time, nos. 43-59 (Box 163)
  - Proud callies, no. 1 (Box 163)
  - Re-covery and re-emergence, nos. 1-2 (Box 163)
  - Re-evaluation counseling teacher, nos. 1-18 (Box 164)
  - RC teacher, nos. 19-20 (Box 164)
  - Re-evaluation Sister nos.3-7 (Box 164)
  - Re-evaluation Well-Being nos. 3-4 (Box 164)
  - Reference Point nos. 12-18 (Box 165)
  - Priests' and Nuns' Newsletter no.1 (Box 165)
  - Re-evaluation Counseling for Jewish Liberation nos.1-5 (Box 165)
  - Seeds and Crystals nos.2-4 (Box 165)
  - Side by Side no.1 (Box 165)
  - Songs on our Way nos.1-2 (Box 165)
  - Tee Hee nos.1-9 (Box 165)
  - Upcoming nos.1-2 (Box 165)
  - Well-Being no.1 (Box 165)
  - Wide World Changing nos.1-2 (Box 165)
  - Working for a Living nos.1-4 (Box 165)
  - Young and Powerful nos.1-2 (Box 165)
  - Young People's Newsletter no.1 (Box 165)
- Series 19. Severe Tire Damage Records
  Mark Weiser was the drummer for Severe Tire Damage, a band that routinely performed live on the Internet.
  This small series contains ephemera relating to Weiser's participation in Severe Tire Damage.
  - Severe Tire Damage (Box 166, Folder 1)
  - Business cards (Box 166, Folder 2)
  - Photographs (Box 166, Folder 3)
- Series 20. Memorabilia
  - American Civil Liberties Union membership card (Box 166, Folder 4)
  - Driver's License Maryland (Box 166, Folder 5)
  - International Certification of Vaccination (Box 166, Folder 6)
  - Security Identification Badge (Box 166, Folder 7)
  - Car Title (Box 166, Folder 8)
  - Xerox PARC Personnel Matchbook Covers (Box 166, Folder 9)
- Series 21. Artifacts
  - Xerox Inventor Award, 1996 (Box 167)
  - Xerox Inventor Award, 1993 (Box 167)
  - CSL bean bag (Box 167)
  - International Conference on Distributed Computing Medal, 1994 (Box 167)
  - Xerox Medal, 1989 (Box 167)
  - PARC 25 serving Bowl, 1970-1995 (Box 167)
  - PARC Follies Star, 1991 (Box 167)
  - Usenix Annual Technical Conference: Invited Drummer pass, 1997 (Box 167)
  - DocuWorld paperweight, 1997 (Box 167)
  - Xerox Pin (Box 167)
  - Timex DataLink silver watch (Box 168)
  - Radio Shack Spell Checker and calculator Ruler (Box 168)
  - .WAV jammer 16 bit stereo sound card (Box 168)
  - Light pen (Box 168)
  - Xerox PARC pen (Box 168)
  - FUJI Xerox Japanese print hanging napkin (Box 168)
  - Unidentifiable Electronic Object (Box 168)
  - Unidentifiable Electronic Object (Box 168)
  - Unidentifiable Electronic Object (Box 168)
  - UNIX Decorative license plate (Box 168)
  - Computer Lib*Pledge Plaque (Box 168)
  - Decorative box containing two brass engraved and colored plates (Box 168)
  - Timex DataLink Flash PC Companion (Box 169)
  - Styrofoam rectangle with picture (Box 169)
  - Styrofoam rectangle with picture (Box 169)
  - Radio Shack computer (Box 169)
  - Security Infrared Remote (Box 169)
  - Beeper with chain (Box 169)
  - Nintendo Game Boy (Box 169)
  - Radio Shack Executive Planner (Box 169)
  - Beeper (Box 169)
  - Beeper (Box 169)
  - Mpad (Box 169)
  - Secret Sender 6000 (Box 169)
  - Message sender diary JD-3500 (Box 169)
  - My Super Magic Diary JD 6500 (Box 169)
  - Data Blaster (Box 169)
  - Unidentifiable Electronic Object (Box 169)
  - Unidentifiable Electronic Object (Box 169)
  - Video Guide (Box 170)
  - Video Guide AC Adapter (Box 170)
  - Clear Plastic pen shaped stick (Box 170)
  - VideoShow Presenter (Box 170)
  - Sony Video8 HandyCam (Box 171)
  - Sony HandyCam Adapter (Box 171)
  - Motorola Cellphone battery recharger (Box 172)
  - Motorola Cellphone battery recharger adapter (Box 172)
  - Five button box (Box 172)
  - Three Button box with cord (Box 172)
  - Light pen with cord (Box 172)
  - Hewlett-Packard Accessory (Box 172)
  - Hewlett-Packard Accessory (Box 172)
  - Hewlett-Packard Accessory (Box 172)
  - Black leather business card wallet (Box 172)
  - Electric Organizer (Box 173)
  - Unidentifiable Electronic Object (Box 173)
  - Pro Presenter in zipper case (Box 173)
  - MobiDem (Box 173)
  - Refalo Electric Planner (Box 173)
  - Data Discman Electronic Book Player (Box 173)
  - Flashback Remote (Box 173)
  - Voice Organizer (Box 174)
  - Remote Point Transmitter (Box 174)
  - TV Remote (Box 174)
  - TV Remote (Box 174)
  - Unidentifiable Electronic Object (Box 174)
  - Remote (Box 174)
  - Docking Station (Box 174)
  - Docking Station with cord (Box 174)
  - Sun Operating System Release 2.0 tape, 1986 November 18 (Box 175)
  - Sun Operating System Release 2.0 tape, 1987 May 6 (Box 175)
  - Video Tape for Helical Scan (Box 175)
  - Unidentifiable Electronic Object (Box 175)
  - Unidentifiable Electronic Object (Box 175)
  - AC Adapter (Box 175)
  - Virtual Is It's Own Reward Button (Box 175)
  - Xerox PARC Sunglasses (Box 175)
  - Bag of Motors (Box 176)
  - Illinois Grade School Band & Orchestra Gold Concert District Medal (Box 176)
  - Illinois Grade School Band & Orchestra Bronze Band District Medal (Box 176)
  - Illinois Grade School Band & Orchestra Concert Silver District Medal (Box 176)
  - Earphone (Box 176)
  - Spool of Copper Wire (Box 176)
  - Ball Crystal pendant (Box 176)
  - Unidentifiable Electronic Object (Box 176)
  - Sketchbook (Box 177)
  - Color printing ain't easy! [realia], n.d., 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - Responsive environment: Xerox Palo Alto Research Center [realia], n.d., 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - X [realia], n.d., 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - PARC 25, 1970-1995: Xerox Palo Alto Research Center [realia], 1995, 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - LiveWorks: a Xerox Company [realia], n.d., 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - Coyote Hill [realia], n.d., 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - PARC '94 [realia], n.d., 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - We didn't want your operating system ... this is what we want! [realia], n.d., 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - STD ... Catch it [realia], n.d., 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - Severe Tire Damage Rolling Stones Virtual Tour [realia], 1994, 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - Xerox PARC [realia], n.d., 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
  - The computer bowl [realia], n.d., 1 t-shirt (Box 178)
- Series 22. David Weiser Papers
  David Weiser, Mark Weiser's father, was a teacher at Shimer College. During his tenure at the college, he became involved in a dispute with the then-president of the University. He ultimately lead a successful campaign to have the president expelled from the University.
  This series contains correspondence, notes, diaries and other journal entries, as well as documentation on David Weiser campaign to oust president Mullin of Shimer College from his seat.
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 179, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 179, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 179, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 179, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 179, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 179, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 179, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 179, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 179, Folder 9)
  - Bruditt-Weiser Correspondence (Box 179, Folder 10)
  - Editorials (Box 179, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (Box 179, Folder 12)
  - Papers re: President Mullin, Shimer College (Box 179, Folder 13)
  - Shimer College [1 of 3] (Box 179, Folder 14)
  - Shimer College [2 of 3] (Box 179, Folder 15)
  - Shimer College [3 of 3] (Box 179, Folder 16)
  - Computation notebook, Baker 94, David W. Weiser (Box 179, Folder 17)
  - Notebook with notes re: Scientific change, ed. by A.C. Crombie, 1963, n.d. (Box 179, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 179, Folder 19)
  - Personal file (Box 179, Folder 20)
  - On myth and communication, n.d., ams (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - Lecture notes, n.d. (Box 180, Folder 2)
  - Current to do brief (Box 180, Folder 3)
  - General (Box 180, Folder 4)
  - Reprints (Box 180, Folder 5)
  - Chemistry (Box 180, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1951 Feb. 2 - 1951 Apr. 11, disbound spiral notebook (Box 180, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 1963 Aug. 12 - 1964 June 1 (Box 180, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1964 June 20, disbound leaf from spiral notebook (Box 180, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1966 July 1 - 1966 Dec. 7 (Box 180, Folder 10)
  - Journal entry, 1966 Dec. 10, 1 card (Box 180, Folder 11)
  - Journal, 1966 Dec., on looseleaf paper (Box 180, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 1966 Dec. 13 - 1967 Mar. 3 (Box 180, Folder 13)
  - Journal, 1967 Mar. 5 - 1967 May 9 (Box 180, Folder 14)
  - Journal, 1967, on looseleaf paper (Box 180, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 1967 Sept. 9 - 1967 Dec. 21 (Box 180, Folder 16)
  - Journal, 1968 Sept. 20 - 1969 June (Box 180, Folder 17)
  - Journal, 1970 Jan. 15 - 1970 Dec. 17, on looseleaf paper (Box 180, Folder 18)
  - Journal, 1971 Jan. 1 - 1975 Nov., on looseleaf paper (Box 180, Folder 19)
  - Journal, 1976 Oct. 27 - 1977 Apr. 8 (Box 180, Folder 20)
  - Personal journal / diary, 1978 - 1979; n.d. (Box 180, Folder 21)
  - Journal, n.d. (Box 180, Folder 22)
  - A confession / David Weiser, n.d. (Box 180, Folder 23)